

Computer Vision Researcher

Roles: Researcher, Supervisor, Lecturer, Invited speaker, Engineer.

Email: Silvia[dot]Laura[dot]Pintea[at]gmail[dot]com

Webpage: http://silvialaurapintea.github.io

My work is in the field of Computer Vision and Deep Learning, where I have extensive experience with video and image analysis, specifically scale-invariance, geometric priors, motion analysis and regression problems.

My current focus is medical image analysis for cancer detection and segmentation.

EDUCATION

PhD	Computer Vision
Institution	University van Amsterdam Amsterdam, NL
Period	2011 - 2016
Thesis Title	Continuous Learning in Computer Vision
Focus	Motion prediction, object localization, video representation learning
\mathbf{MSc}	Artificial Intelligence
Institution	University van Amsterdam Amsterdam, NL
Period /Avg. Grade	$2009 - 2011 \mid 8.31 \text{ (out of } 10)$
Focus	Machine Learning, Computer Vision, Neural Networks, Game Theory.
\mathbf{BSc}	Computer Science
Institution	University of Bucharest, Faculty of Mathematics and Computer Science, Bucharest, RO
Period /Avg. grade	$2005 - 2008 \mid 9.40 \text{ (out of } 10)$
Focus	Algorithms and data structures, Object oriented programming, Formal methods.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Assistant Professor (Tenure Track)	Vision Lab, Delft University of Technology, Delft, NL Focus on Deep Learning scale-invariance and efficiency
Period	July 2020 — February 2022
$\mathbf{PostDoc}$	Vision Lab, Delft University of Technology, Delft, NL
Period	July 2018 — July 2020
Job Description	Geophysical seismic image analysis with the use of Deep Learning.
$\mathbf{PostDoc}$	Vision Lab, Delft University of Technology, Delft, NL
Period	July 2016 — July 2018
Job Description	Working on the "Technology in Motion" project with the Leiden University Medical Center towards diagnosing and treatment of motor diseases. Project link: https://tim.lumc.nl
R&D Engineer	Layar/Blippar, Amsterdam, NL
Period	January — June 2016
Job Description	Adding state-of-the-art Deep Learning methods for large-scale image retrieval, feature match-
	ing and binarization algorithms.

KEY PUBLICATIONS

Complete list of publications: https://scholar.google.nl/citations?user=shTkx9EAAAAJ&hl=en

[&]quot;Resolution learning in deep convolutional networks using scale-space theory", SL Pintea, N Tomen, SF Goes, M Loog, JC van Gemert, Transactions on Image Processing (TIP), 2021.

[&]quot;Deep continuous networks", N Tomen, SL Pintea, JC Van Gemert", International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML), 2021

[&]quot;No frame left behind: Full Video Action Recognition", X Liu, SL Pintea, FK Nejadasl, O Booij, JC van Gemert. Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2020.

[&]quot;Déjà Vu: Motion Prediction in Static Images.", SL Pintea, JC van Gemert, AWM Smeulders, European Conference on Computer Vision, 2014, (http://github.com/SilviaLauraPintea/DejaVu)

Reviewer CVPR, ECCV/ICCV, BMVC, ICPR, ICML, NeurIPS, TIP, IJCV

CONFERENCE PARTICIPATION International participation: CVPR 2021, ICCV 2021, ECCV 2020, ICIP 2018,

ICIP 2016, workshop ECCV 2016, ECCV 2014

Local participation: NCCV 2019, NCCV 2018, ICT.Open 2016, ICT.Open 2012 INVITED SPEAKER

NVPHBV 2017, Nuctech meeting Delft, Delft-Leiden Deep Learning Seminars

2019.

Deep Learning MSc course TUDelft, 2019 Invited lecturer

LECTURER BSc Image Processing course, MSc Computer Vision course at TUDelft

TEACHING ASSISTANT BSc Short Course on Pattern Recognition, MSc Computer Vision course.

Tobias Stahl, Yichao Zhang, Chengqiu Zhang, Xilin Li, Yue Liu, Omar Hommos, MSC SUPERVISOR

Xiaoming Wen, Jian Zheng, Ziyu Bao, Yordan Dimitrov, Nikhil Saldanha.

Vedran Vukotic, Abolfazi Nadi, Yancong Lin, Xin Liu. PhD supervisor

> AWARD Outstanding Reviewer award CVPR 2021, ICCV 2021;

> > Best paper award for the Workshop on Hands, ECCV 2018.

Languages & Tools Python, PyTorch, TensorFlow, C/C++, Caffe, Torch, PHP, Java, OpenCV,

Dlib, Shogun, LibSVM, VlFeat, Yael, Cuda-Convnet, Matlab.

References Dr. Ir. Femke Vossepoel (F[dot]C[dot]Vossepoel[at]tudelft[dot]nl)

Dr. Marco Loog (M.Loog@tudelft.nl)

Dr. Jan van Gemert (J[dot]C[dot]vanGemert[at]tudelft[dot]nl)